<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NENRIKIDO</title>
    <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on NENRIKIDO</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://nenrikido.neocities.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bye-bye Bootstrap</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/bye-bye-bootstrap/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 18:42:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/bye-bye-bootstrap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is a site update wrapped up in a diary entry, so I&amp;rsquo;ll start off with a quick rundown of those updates:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New start menu&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New sitemap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more Bootstrap! (lots of style changes, ctrl f5 if anything is off)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still so much left to do, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying not to put too much pressure on myself. This might be my last major update for awhile (although I have a few planned shrines &amp;amp; posts which might make it out before all is said and done). My Windows laptop (primary) restarted 14 times in the last 24 hours, which is about as fun as it sounds. Still working on transferring all my shit to an older laptop, but yeah, things are just in flux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was whilst anxiously procrastinating moving stuff that I started randomly scraping at the Bootstrap on my site like burnt egg on a nonstick pan, and before I knew it, it turned into a whole thing. Had to comb through all my code for the fourth time, and although I&amp;rsquo;m pretty tired, look, new start menu!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;./images/blog/052823/start.gif&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;start &#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/052823/start.gif&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; loading=&#34;&#34;  width=&#34;&#34; height=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d previously been using Bootstrap&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://getbootstrap.com/docs/5.3/components/modal/&#34;&gt;JS modal&lt;/a&gt; to handle the start menu, but I learned more about vanilla modals when I was working on the &lt;a href=&#34;./code/preview/sakura/&#34;&gt;Sakura page theme&lt;/a&gt; and decided to implement it myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;m getting ahead of myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those unaware, Bootstrap is a front-end library&amp;ndash;arguably the most popular of its kind&amp;ndash;that you can drop into your website for extremely quick, basic styling. Without touching a single line of CSS or JS yourself, you can design a serviceable website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And many, many, &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; do. Bootstrap&amp;rsquo;s simplicity means that it&amp;rsquo;s the first recommendation to novice web developers who are intimidated by or disinterested in CSS. Thus, a sort of digital sameface has emerged, a visual homogenization of the internet. A website that is relying on Bootstrap for its design is immediately identifiable, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t realize you know what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. Peruse through some of &lt;a href=&#34;https://getbootstrap.com/docs/5.2/examples/&#34;&gt;these examples&lt;/a&gt;, and you&amp;rsquo;ll get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hotly debated and ever-controversial amongst front-end web developers, I&amp;rsquo;ve often felt defensive over allegations of how Bootstrap is destroying web design. Although Boostrap is fairly opinionated in its design language, you can always override its default styling, after all. &lt;em&gt;Besides&lt;/em&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d tell myself, &lt;em&gt;I use Bootstrap for its grid system, not its styling.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, I also have strong opinions about design, so I&amp;rsquo;ve often butted heads with Bootstrap. I also have a deep affection for Bootstrap because it saved my ass when I had no idea what I was doing (Cicadagate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about CSS is that it&amp;rsquo;s super easy to get started with, but it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to actually master, and you often think you know way more than you actually do. Tools like Bootstrap are excellent at compensating for these weaknesses&amp;ndash;in my case, I was (and am) generally weak with grids and flex. This translated to weakness with responsive CSS and layouts, which made it very difficult to achieve my specific design goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t totally my fault; CSS grid wasn&amp;rsquo;t fully adopted until 2017 and flexbox didn&amp;rsquo;t get cross-browser support until 2014. This stuff is constantly evolving! And I realize that I, too, must evolve. Frankly, there&amp;rsquo;s no real reason to use Bootstrap now that there are better tools. Back when I first used it, it was an emergency situation, and although I&amp;rsquo;m grateful, it got me into bad habits and let me stagnate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of what it was costing me in my learning, it was also costing my site performance. Dependencies slow your site down, and something as robust as Bootstrap that loads in the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag (meaning it has to load before the rest of your site will) can cause a noticeable performance hit. I&amp;rsquo;m already using a lot more Javascript than I meant to, so I don&amp;rsquo;t want to slow my site down even more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially because, well, I was not using it for its design functions. I was primarily using it for its &lt;a href=&#34;https://getbootstrap.com/docs/5.3/layout/grid/&#34;&gt;column system&lt;/a&gt; (which really is quite useful, and has taught me a lot about what I want from boilerplate CSS), which is achievable without Bootstrap, if a bit more annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up making a general purpose .row flex class and then adding utility classes for different row alignments (center, space-between, space-evenly, etc.) to maintain some of my row construction. I also created a general .grid that auto-fills space and added a few utility classes for column sizing. This got me a long way, but there were still various annoyances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy to say my HTML is much cleaner now that I&amp;rsquo;m separating concerns more clearly, which often means less repetition. Although I&amp;rsquo;m still using utility classes, much more CSS is where it belongs&amp;hellip;in the stylesheet, that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was already in there digging around, I went ahead and changed all the window sizing from responsive units to pixel units (which makes it more responsive in some ways, less responsive in others.) Example: Gallery used to be locked into 4 columns, now it&amp;rsquo;ll shrink to 3 at a certain size. I&amp;rsquo;m still not happy with all of the shrinking behavior, but let&amp;rsquo;s put that on a list of things to do&amp;hellip;some other time. I&amp;rsquo;ll put it right under fixing the search function, which I&amp;rsquo;ve tried and failed to resolve twice now. JS experts hit me up whenever lol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did end up making a sitemap&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s a modified version of this &lt;a href=&#34;https://hugocodex.org/add-ons/nested-menu/&#34;&gt;nested menu add-on&lt;/a&gt; for Hugo. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything that did exactly what I want, and as I am still very intimidated by Go, this will do for now. I really love how powerful Hugo is. I will do my best to learn more and more&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways, my mother cut my hair because it was getting unwieldy. I thought this was greatly symbolic in light of my breakup with Bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;./images/blog/052823/haircut.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;start &#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/052823/haircut.jpg&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; loading=&#34;&#34;  width=&#34;&#34; height=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farewell, friend!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;./images/blog/052823/hair.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;start &#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/052823/hair.jpg&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; loading=&#34;&#34;  width=&#34;&#34; height=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 months later: A Neocities Reflection</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/neocities-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 21:50:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/neocities-reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, what&amp;rsquo;s up. I haven&amp;rsquo;t made a blog post in awhile, mostly because the &lt;a href=&#34;./microblog&#34;&gt;microblog&lt;/a&gt; exists as a more convenient place for me to dump my half-baked thoughts, and also because I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished any of the actual guides or posts that I want to post here (sorry).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is more of a diary entry reflecting on some stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed while being on Neocities. It&amp;rsquo;s been a little over two months since I started this site, and I still have such a long way to go (keep an eye out for new shrines soon btw&amp;hellip;), but I&amp;rsquo;m really happy with how much I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so far. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to continue moving forward with Neocities, but I do have some observations about the community element of it, and about online communities (Discord, Tumblr, Twitter, etc.) in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Old web nostalgia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a ton of old web nostalgia, which I guess is to be expected on a platform modelled after Geocities. I also have a healthy dose of nostalgia for old forum aesthetics and table-based layouts, but I do think some people take it a little far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m 26 and I&amp;rsquo;m still too young to treat dial-up and AOL messenger as if it was ever a major part my life. Web 1.0 ended around 2005, when I was still in elementary school, and I&amp;rsquo;m older than a lot of users here. What little I do recall of the old web is a mixed bag&amp;ndash;I remember excruciating wait times for webpages, obvious adults on Neopets trying to lure kids into private chatrooms, and just an overall lack of organization and cohesion. There was also a lot to love, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it really benefits anyone to pine for an aestheticized and frankly fictionalized phase of internet culture that will never exist again. It was wild and untamed &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; it was brand new, and there&amp;rsquo;s no way to re-capture the novelty of the late 90s/early 2000s internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, I think it&amp;rsquo;s more about re-experiencing childhood for a lot of people than anything else. And I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s wrong or anything, I just find the justifications for this nostalgia strange. Like, why do you have to pretend the Kid Pix widget on your site is political resistance against corporate internet when we both know it&amp;rsquo;s just because it makes you feel warm and fuzzy to remember simpler times? It&amp;rsquo;s okay to be self-indulgent on your personal website! I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why it has to be more than that. Which isn&amp;rsquo;t to say you can&amp;rsquo;t have fun &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; try to make a statement, it just sometimes feels like people don&amp;rsquo;t realize they&amp;rsquo;re allowed to enjoy things for the sake of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for a lot of people who are definitely too young to have experienced it, I dunno, it&amp;rsquo;s weird. It&amp;rsquo;s like teenagers projecting the politics they imagine Web 1.0 held and prescribing a set of aesthetics to those politics. I think it&amp;rsquo;s generally a bad idea to treat ideology like fashion, but I think social media has done a lot to normalize this practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which leads me into my next observation&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Politics in online communities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think we messed up by insisting to ourselves and each other that Gen Z is somehow ontologically woke. Many, many young people online have deeply conservative impulses that they&amp;rsquo;ve never questioned. Ever notice how it&amp;rsquo;s always the people with &amp;ldquo;be gay do crime&amp;rdquo; in their bios who get mad at you for pirating their blorbos? The state of political consciousness is so grim that the people siding with Disney on stricter copyright laws think they&amp;rsquo;re anti-capitalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t escape me that a lot of the politics people ascribe to the old web are just&amp;hellip;entirely fabricated. For example, this whole &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t steal my code&amp;rdquo; thing I keep seeing is almost always coming from the exact same people who wax nostalgic for the old web. Girl! If you scold people over CSS theft, you would not have lasted a day on the actual old web. You are &amp;ldquo;good old days&amp;quot;ing something that never even existed! Besides, one of the best things about the old web was how collaborative it was. Frantic possessiveness over HTML and CSS is antithetical to the ethos of the old web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s inevitable that when you create a social dynamic where people are expected to immediately have an opinion about everything, they&amp;rsquo;ll base those opinions on vibes (read: social conditioning) rather than theory, data, or logic. This is also why you constantly see openly conservative politics paraded all over social media as if it&amp;rsquo;s novel or brave. If someone has no ideological base, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to convince them something is radical as long as you use the right framing. But if you scratch off the coat of progressive paint, it&amp;rsquo;s abundantly obvious that scorching hot takes like &amp;ldquo;let women wear makeup&amp;rdquo; are, in fact, neutered and useless. If your politics are all just pithy, nonthreatening slogans a CNN pundit might tweet, your politics are necessarily not-radical and probably actually strengthening repressive, hegemonic narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t just an issue on Neocities; it&amp;rsquo;s become the status quo for political discourse online. So I did expect it to some degree, but I think I was overly optimistic. I guess I thought that a platform like this would be more &amp;ldquo;here&amp;rsquo;s some Linux guides and FOSS recommendations&amp;rdquo; and less &amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;re a fascist if you don&amp;rsquo;t think heteroromantic asexuals are queer&amp;rdquo; microblogger discourse. It is surreal to see people continuously re-litigating 2014 Tumblr discourse. I recognize so many of the common talking points online because I was there when that discourse was born, and I am still here now that discourse&amp;rsquo;s bloated corpse has washed back up to shore. I wish we&amp;rsquo;d let it rest. Most of it was stupid infighting among bored teenagers then, and it still is now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to grow up and find real things to care about, not triple down on the apparent life-or-death seriousness of fanfiction politics or whatever. Which isn&amp;rsquo;t to say you can&amp;rsquo;t get into some inane, petty discourse as a treat (I do this), but I think you have to keep it in perspective. Could you explain this topic to an offline person without a 3 hour YouTube essay? No? Then it&amp;rsquo;s probably too insular and niche to justify the energy you&amp;rsquo;re putting into arguing about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The promise of community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am constantly falling into a trap. I think the concept of community is so fantastic that I continuously search for it on every platform, and I am continuously disappointed when the reality doesn&amp;rsquo;t meet my expectations. There is a certain community on Neocities that recently shut down. I never partook in it, but I was hoping for its success, and reading the moratorium has been a bit disheartening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe this is just the byproduct of an increasingly polarized internet, but it feels like people are getting worse and worse with boundaries. It seems some aren&amp;rsquo;t content with setting boundaries for themselves&amp;ndash;they want to set yours, too. Extremely online spaces always seem to devolve into masses of paranoid people policing each other. I mean the type of people who&amp;rsquo;ll emotionally blackmail you into walking on eggshells, who&amp;rsquo;ll tell you what you&amp;rsquo;re allowed to watch and read, who you&amp;rsquo;re allowed to speak to and associate with, and what thoughts you&amp;rsquo;re allowed to think. All this while totally convinced they&amp;rsquo;re moral paragons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently saw a post on Tumblr that essentially said we need to learn how to simply dislike people without manufacturing a moral justification. It had nearly 100,000 notes; tons of people were acting like this was some long overdue revelation, and I find that unnerving. Very bleak when we need a post to explain that your personal dislike of someone doesn&amp;rsquo;t make them evil!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can admit I used to fall into this tribal thinking, but it&amp;rsquo;s a miserable way to live, and I saw people get torn apart by their online peers for things that would&amp;rsquo;ve been total non-issues just a year later. When you create a category of person it&amp;rsquo;s morally justified to destroy, you create an incentive to put anyone you dislike in that category. This is especially true for people who are bullies to their core but desperately need to maintain moral superiority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not saying you should tolerate &lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt;. I think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to set boundaries. But I also think that this weird, entitled vigilance people exhibit goes way beyond that. Once you start publicly shaming random no-name people for their associations rather than just blocking and moving on, you turn into a sanctimonious little hall monitor in my eyes and I am deeply skeptical of your motivations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have seen the justification for this sort of behavior being, &amp;ldquo;the small web is about curating your own space, we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t allow (xyz).&amp;rdquo; First off, who is &amp;lsquo;we&amp;rsquo;? When did I agree to this? Second, who said that&amp;rsquo;s what the small web is about? Where is this memo? Third, if the small web is about curating your space, why are you trying to tell other people how to curate theirs? Who even decides what constitutes the &amp;lsquo;small web&amp;rsquo; to begin with? What is your goal here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely refuse to engage in this sort of triablism anymore, but it seems that&amp;rsquo;s all that&amp;rsquo;s available these days. There&amp;rsquo;s no community, just self-cannibalizing cliques. Very sad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ll wrap up this post here, but in the interest of cultivating community, DO please consider sending me an email if you: are an eldest daughter, are a Haruki Murakami hater, have strong opinions about betta fish, are skeptical that dinosaurs were real, have been accused of being pretentious by someone who exclusively reads YA fiction, are a woman with moderate to severe scoliosis, step on sidewalk cracks with purpose, or have ever earnestly cast a spell on someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you next time!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Updates</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/site-updates-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 02:29:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/site-updates-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TLDR:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is now a &lt;a href=&#34;./library&#34;&gt;library&lt;/a&gt; of various types of media (from books to video). It&amp;rsquo;s listed in the Start Menu and on the Index page now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;./shrines&#34;&gt;shrines&lt;/a&gt; page finally looks presentable. There&amp;rsquo;s still just&amp;hellip;well, Cole. For now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now part of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://nuthead.neocities.org/&#34;&gt;null&lt;/a&gt; webring, which is viewable on the &lt;a href=&#34;./links&#34;&gt;links&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changed out the body font for the &amp;ldquo;black&amp;rdquo; theme. I think it looks nicer now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;blog-post&#34;&gt;BLOG POST:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was a child, my local library held all sorts of events. I have warm memories of summer reading challenges, overnight reading lock-ins, and Ghibli movie nights hosted on a small, bulky TV we&amp;rsquo;d all crowd around. Off-brand dark cola and cheese pizza still remind me of late nights reading, the thrill of being a child in a library at 3AM curled up with a Lois Duncan book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In elementary school, I often spent recess in the school library, flopped over a bean bag as I worked my way through books methodically. I would set goals for myself (&amp;ldquo;I will read this entire shelf&amp;rdquo;) and proudly proclaim them to the librarian, inventing tracking sheets and hunting for challengers to compete with. (Surprisingly, this was not an especially effective recruiting tactic.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started struggling with mental health issues in 7th grade, I&amp;rsquo;d often retreat to the school library to calm myself down. The school librarians, eventually coaxing out the details, invented a &amp;ldquo;librarian assistant&amp;rdquo; position just for me, complete with a &amp;ldquo;librarian pass&amp;rdquo; that allowed me to leave class whenever I wanted. I also got a special clipboard to survey classmates on what books to order. I&amp;rsquo;d often sneak in a few extra orders of my favorite shoujo manga while the head librarian shared homemade sugar cookies with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school, I spent so much time in the library that they gave me admin privileges. I used to have a bad habit of dropping by on my way to the bus stop at the end of the day to get another book, and I&amp;rsquo;d invariably get so distracted I missed the bus. A girl I liked approached me to be friends, so naturally, I invited her to the library, a proposal her mom found so confusing she called my mom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In college, I flirted with food service before remembering I, well, &lt;em&gt;love libraries&lt;/em&gt;. So then I spent four years working in libraries on two different campuses. I worked in Digital Collections archiving and OCR&amp;rsquo;ing fragile documents, then after I moved to a new school, started working in in Archives &amp;amp; Special Collections. After awhile, I ended up with a dual position in the Digital Services department, splitting my summers into collecting archival materials and then later scanning and uploading those materials. And truly, I loved it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I graduated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to a few Reasons, I can&amp;rsquo;t go to the public library all that often anymore. I also don&amp;rsquo;t have the academic credentials to access to databases anymore, which has been pretty devastating. (At least JSTOR still lets you check out 100 articles a month?) Anyways, I miss the library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s scarily easy to just stop reading. In fact, after a few years of not really reading much, it got harder and harder to get back into it. And maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just being dramatic, but I realized that for me, a life comprised of just fandom-y content and goofing off is incomprehensibly miserable. So I decided I needed to start reading again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to share some of the stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve read with you, dear reader&amp;hellip;for free! Partly because I think it&amp;rsquo;s cool to have a webpage of stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve found illuminating, partly because I think open access to information is important, and partly because I think it&amp;rsquo;s easier to read things when someone plops it down in front of you, and I think we could all probably stand to read more. I only found a ton of stuff on that list because of random bloggers posting snippets, so hopefully something there is useful to someone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the past few days setting up the library, and I think it&amp;rsquo;s a nice start. I won&amp;rsquo;t pretend to remember the ins-and-outs of every title (hey, it&amp;rsquo;s been a long time, okay), but I know many of my beliefs have been informed, changed, and/or otherwise challenged by the stuff there. I know I&amp;rsquo;m forgetting a lot of titles, and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve had a hard time getting ahold of. I also feel like the library is a bit too serious right now, maybe, and I&amp;rsquo;m worried about how obviously skewed it is. I don&amp;rsquo;t need it to be a &amp;ldquo;neutral&amp;rdquo; thing, but I&amp;rsquo;m noticing some glaring gaps in the sort of content I&amp;rsquo;d like there. Can&amp;rsquo;t hurt to have more incentive to read though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to someday tackle a more ambitious digital librarianship project that really digs into databases and complex methods of sorting data, but for now&amp;hellip;check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evangelion, Learning, &amp; Moving</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/evangelion-learning-moving/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 03:51:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/evangelion-learning-moving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve been really struggling to articulate my thoughts lately, so i&amp;rsquo;m hoping that some late night blogging can get my brain unstuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve been rewatching the evangelion anime and forgot it&amp;rsquo;s like&amp;hellip;good? i think its legacy is so complicated and i&amp;rsquo;ve grown so used to eye-rolling at eva fans i forgot how compelling the plot beats and characters are. so that&amp;rsquo;s been fun. it&amp;rsquo;s been nice languishing in 90s anime. the moody soundtracks and color grading often felt so intimate and pensive in a way i think has become less popular over time (not to sound like an anime hipster).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i haven&amp;rsquo;t watched any of the rebuild movies in like a decade, but i do want to watch those next. i think i still have the first 2 on blu ray lmao, but i hardly remember what happened. i;m sort of walking in with a bias that i won&amp;rsquo;t like the rebuild movies as much, but i want to give them a fair chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;anyways, i find myself a lot more interested in the adult characters now that i am an adult, and it feels like uncovering a whole new layer to the show i wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to appreciate as a child. the misato/kaiji/ritsuko dynamic is especially interesting, and ritsuko in general has caught my attention a lot more than she did before. she just seems so profoundly isolated and the trajectory of her life is so tragic but understandable and even predictable. and i think a lot of people know what it&amp;rsquo;s like to devote everything you have to someone, only to realize you&amp;rsquo;re replaceable to them. that you&amp;rsquo;ve twisted and broken and destroyed yourself for someone who would betray you at the drop of a hat. (i could have fixed her btw). it&amp;rsquo;s just really engaging to me and she&amp;rsquo;s not even one of our primary characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in between all that, i&amp;rsquo;ve been trying (and failing) to get back into bullet journalling because i feel like my life has been a bit of a mess lately. it&amp;rsquo;s been so hard to adjust to a life without the structure of school. part of me wants to say fuck it and go to grad school, part of me fears that&amp;rsquo;s just my way of running away to hide in a warm familiar coccoon. (whoa it&amp;rsquo;s just like eva fr..) it&amp;rsquo;s funny because school always brings out the worst in me and makes me unstable, but i don&amp;rsquo;t know how to exist without it. comfortable chaos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve also been trying to learn javascript, which is extremely frightening to me! i have a bad habit of building things up in my head to be unattainable and giving up before i begin. i don&amp;rsquo;t like doing things i&amp;rsquo;m not good at. it makes me feel stupid. which is a feeling i dislike. but i&amp;rsquo;m sick of the mysticism surrounding javascript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and it&amp;rsquo;s already paying off actually. like i fixed the gallery filter and half of it was just not being so scared of modifying the javascript. and i fixed a lot of muuri issues i was having (the grid now resizes after it loads so elements don&amp;rsquo;t overlap). so onwards and upwards! maybe i will finally fix up the theme code (a friend very kindly wrote it for me) and release it? i get asked a lot about the theme switching, but i still need to (1) resolve the flash of default theme color on page load and (2) create a smoother transition when themes are toggled. (also trying to learn SASS because i actually do understand CSS which makes me feel a little less stupid LMAO.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;anyways, i&amp;rsquo;m still moving. it&amp;rsquo;s been 1 billion trillion years and becomes increasingly unserious but it&amp;rsquo;s just hard okay. i&amp;rsquo;m so fatigued all the time and don&amp;rsquo;t have money for movers so there&amp;rsquo;s a ton of DIY&amp;rsquo;ing that has happened and still needs to happen. i should start taking some vitamin D supplements or something. i have POTS, which a lot of doctors treat as a non-issue, but god i&amp;rsquo;m soo tired all the time it sure feels like an issue. and then i check my pulse and it&amp;rsquo;s like 140 BPM for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m also moving to a much smaller place in a rural town and&amp;hellip;ok actually i forgot where i was going with this. gonna just go to bed, my brain is fried. no. scrambled. eggs. idk it&amp;rsquo;s 4AM. did i mention my sleep schedule was fixed for two (2) days. then daylight savings happened and it was over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;well anyways here is a post for your trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;./images/blog/t.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;t &#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/t.jpg&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; loading=&#34;&#34;  width=&#34;750&#34; height=&#34;568&#34; alt=&#34;A Twitter screencap.&#34;&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Preloader</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/making-a-preloader/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 01:38:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/making-a-preloader/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently decided it might improve user experience to get a loading screen instead of watching the grid unceremoniously disentangle itself. A few experiments later, and here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;./images/blog/preload.gif&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;preload &#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/preload.gif&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; loading=&#34;&#34;  width=&#34;800&#34; height=&#34;381&#34; alt=&#34;A gif of a brief blue loading screen before the website loads.&#34;&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool! The markup isn&amp;rsquo;t too difficult, but I know it would&amp;rsquo;ve saved me time if I stumbled across a tutorial like this earlier, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share how I did it. Here&amp;rsquo;s the code with a different loading icon. You can swap out the background-url with a different one if you like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;codepen&#34; data-height=&#34;300&#34; data-default-tab=&#34;html,result&#34; data-slug-hash=&#34;dygbewv&#34; data-user=&#34;kujara1&#34; style=&#34;height: 300px; box-sizing: border-box; display: flex; align-items: center; justify-content: center; border: 2px solid; margin: 1em 0; padding: 1em;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;span&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&#34;https://codepen.io/kujara1/pen/dygbewv&#34;&gt;
  preloader&lt;/a&gt; by jay (&lt;a href=&#34;https://codepen.io/kujara1&#34;&gt;@kujara1&lt;/a&gt;)
  on &lt;a href=&#34;https://codepen.io&#34;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://cpwebassets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;box-small&#34;&gt;
        &lt;h5&gt;CREDITS&lt;/h5&gt;
        &lt;p&gt; &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://samherbert.net/svg-loaders/&#34;&gt;SVG loaders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yf5d_Zx3AaI&#34;&gt;Preloader script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vanilla-js.com/&#34;&gt;Fade out script&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Updates ...Continued!</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/site-updates-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 20:41:23 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/site-updates-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h5 id=&#34;updates&#34;&gt;UPDATES&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;heyy i spent the day Doing Web Optimization Stuff. i documented some of it for upcoming tutorials (including a masterpost on web optimization that i&amp;rsquo;ll release once this site is, well, optimized.) but the general idea:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;images were compressed, resized, and given thumbnails. gallery should be much quicker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;added alt text to the gallery for screen-readers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;some images are now being lazy loaded, which should also speed things up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finally finished moving the dropbox files to my root directory&amp;hellip;way more tedious than expected. lmao. &lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; so neocities does not let you host mp3 files. this file limitation stuff has been killing me&amp;hellip;first no toml now this! sad!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the rain sounds have been replaced by wind chimes for now. was thinking about switching it up once a month?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is now a preloader screen! i briefly looked into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-build-skeleton-screens-using-css-for-better-user-experience/#differenttypesofskeletonscreens&#34;&gt;skeleton loaders&lt;/a&gt;, which are apparently better practice, but i am just so tired. the preloader is pretty simple, but i actually struggled more than i care to admit, so maybe i should post how i did it more comprehensively soon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tweaked the layout and fixed a bug that made the navigation bar unusable on mobile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;admittedly, i&amp;rsquo;ve always been pretty negligent when it comes to optimizing sites, so this learning endeavor is very new. hopefully this makes for a better UI experience if nothing else. if stuff looks odd, clearing your cache (ctrl + f5) might fix it. feel free to report any issues though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;tip-of-the-day&#34;&gt;TIP OF THE DAY&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in VS code, did you know you can create multiple cursors for super fast edits by holding &lt;code&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt; while you click? &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/docs/editor/codebasics#_multiple-selections-multicursor&#34;&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s true&lt;/a&gt;! reading the docs is actually helpful it turns out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;etc&#34;&gt;ETC.&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i wish i had cool life anecdotes to offer, but i have done nothing but this lately! here&amp;rsquo;s the soundtrack to my web dev stuff these days&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&#34;border-radius:12px&#34; src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/album/5XjZ6xhbPbALPVGd5Zx0Cw?utm_source=generator&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;352&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;man this has been a lot to deal with. i am going to go smoke and reply to emails like god intended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Overhaul</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/site-overhaul/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2023 02:28:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/site-overhaul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;i started making this website around 3 weeks ago. if you told me then that within that time, i&amp;rsquo;d write the site, then re-write it with web components, then re-write it again except with a static site generator, i&amp;rsquo;d believe you. i have a near-pathological need for clear, simple, clean things. my closet is sorted by color and item type. i buy little desk dividers to keep my drawers tidy. the only icon on my desktop is the recycle bin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so yes, i have marie kondo&amp;rsquo;d the site. this has happened before, so i probably should have anticipated it. i was already planning to make some changes, and then one thing just led to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hahahugoshortcodes0hbhb-new-library&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa-regular fa-moon&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; new library&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i have broken up with a few frameworks for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/haltu/muuri&#34;&gt;muuri&lt;/a&gt;, an extremely versatile javascript library layout engine. seriously, it combines 3 (!!) frameworks i was using. AND enables the draggable windows. i&amp;rsquo;m still pretty intimidated by muuri as it requires a bit more configuration than i&amp;rsquo;m comfortable with yet, but i&amp;rsquo;m working it out. big thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://codepen.io/ugokuweb/pen/yLaxBNE&#34;&gt;this codepen&lt;/a&gt; for the gallery filter. anyways, look, drag and drop!
&lt;a href=&#34;./images/blog/dragndrop.gif&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;dragndrop &#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/dragndrop.gif&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; loading=&#34;&#34;  width=&#34;&#34; height=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;expect things to be buggy, especially on mobile. but what are you doing on mobile anyways&amp;hellip;grow up! just kidding. i&amp;rsquo;ll debug it eventually. probably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hahahugoshortcodes2hbhb-now-built-with-hugo&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa-regular fa-star&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  now built with hugo&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you may also notice blog posts are different! that&amp;rsquo;s actually what started this whole endeavor. i finally decided that hugo is famous for building blogs for a reason and i&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to learn more about &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/taxonomies/&#34;&gt;taxonomies&lt;/a&gt; anyways. (now blog posts have tags and this lowkey looks like a tumblr blog. can&amp;rsquo;t help wandering home&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;moving the site to hugo was pretty agonizing at times, but i feel good about it. with the help of shortcodes and partials, i shrank my code to something much more manageable and legible. my gallery page went from 452 lines to 266 lines! the markup is shorter and much easier to understand. and markdown is just soo much easier to deal with than HTML. plus i finally finished moving (most of) my files off of dropbox and can rest assured they&amp;rsquo;re easier to sort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;before:
&lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/before.png&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; &gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;after:
&lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/after.png&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; &gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;another example, pulled from the links page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;before:
&lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/before-1.png&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; &gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;after:
&lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/after-1.png&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; &gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;see what i mean&amp;hellip;that&amp;rsquo;s hugo baby&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hahahugoshortcodes7hbhb-comment-sections--new-guestbook&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa-regular fa-sun&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;  comment sections &amp;amp; new guestbook&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;there are also now comment sections for blog posts!! i don&amp;rsquo;t really know how they work since they&amp;rsquo;re untested, but feel free to leave one? yeah. i also replaced the guestbook. i think the old guestbook service was cute and stuff, but it&amp;rsquo;s (1) not responsive, (2) not very customizable, (3) has ads, (4) an external site, and (5) has poor security practices. so we&amp;rsquo;ll see how that goes? yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hahahugoshortcodes8hbhb-new-content--rss-feed&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-music&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; new content &amp;amp; RSS feed&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i added a few windows to the home page! it now has a blog feed (btw, the RSS feed has been &lt;a href=&#34;./index.xml&#34;&gt;updated&lt;/a&gt;! old one is deprecated.) a few new links here and there, some formatting updates, the commissions page is slooowly in progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hahahugoshortcodes9hbhb-closing&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa-solid fa-rainbow&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; closing&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;anyways, it&amp;rsquo;ll be good to get this over with for now. i get really fixated on tasks and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to step away until it&amp;rsquo;s over with. (although, i did find the time to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cicadacreativemag.com/submit/&#34;&gt;open submissions for cicada&lt;/a&gt;. blinks slowly at you.) i&amp;rsquo;ve been learning a ton about hugo and javascript lately and i think i want to pivot back to writing and drawing for a bit. oh, and i&amp;rsquo;m still moving technically LMAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hopefully the neocities &lt;a href=&#34;https://neocities.org/cli&#34;&gt;CLI tool&lt;/a&gt; is actually easy to use and i don&amp;rsquo;t die. i know Nothing about ruby. i might make a few tutorials in the future, but i guess i worry about giving bad information since i suspect there&amp;rsquo;s still lots that i&amp;rsquo;m doing wrong. still, whatever works, works, so you can expect Something. i&amp;rsquo;ll get this site up on github soon enough. blegh. i&amp;rsquo;m tired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ok talk to you later. here is a song for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&#34;border-radius:12px&#34; src=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/embed/track/38OvTFIg5ZYRow2sA1jgKo?utm_source=generator&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;152&#34; frameBorder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; allow=&#34;autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT: ok i&amp;rsquo;m in hell why is the site so slow. it is so fast on my machine and yet so slow on the internet. science explain. gonna compress my images some more. also note to anyone who may need to be reminded: remember to push your PUBLIC folder to neocities not your project folder. it won&amp;rsquo;t work and your heart will drop&amp;hellip;trust me&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Updates</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/site-updates-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 02:34:47 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/site-updates-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;m still thinking on potential blog layout ideas (at some point, i want each blog post to be its own page so i can link to specific blog posts), but the site is actually coming together much quicker than i thought it would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;anyways i joined the &lt;a href=&#34;https://fujofans.scumsuck.com/&#34;&gt;fujofans&lt;/a&gt; weblisting i saw on &lt;a href=&#34;https://soulbyte.me/&#34;&gt;soulbyte&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; home page and i&amp;rsquo;m so glad i know it exists now. my twitter dn has been yu yu hafujo for like a year and i was worried i wasn&amp;rsquo;t properly conveying my feminist values here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;./images/blog/twt.png&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;fujopride &#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/twt.png&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; loading=&#34;&#34;  width=&#34;&#34; height=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i added some &lt;a href=&#34;./links.html#cool-sites&#34;&gt;new sites&lt;/a&gt; to the cool sites section &amp;amp; some more &lt;a href=&#34;./links.html#web-dev-resources&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt; in the web dev section. i know i should actually be working on my commissions page and whatnot, but it&amp;rsquo;s just more fun to click around random websites. sorry. i also keep forgetting to leave comments or follow the people i list, which is a bit embarrassing. will remedy this eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i also got myself into a bit of a pickle. neocities drag-and-drop functionality is a bit&amp;hellip;let&amp;rsquo;s say unreliable. so at some point i got fed up and just put all my media files in dropbox and linked that way. this is not ideal for like, a lot of reasons, so i&amp;rsquo;ll slowly backtrack and host all the files via neocities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i also still need to clean up some of my older tumblr themes (i actually wince looking at the code now) and put them on my &lt;a href=&#34;./code.html&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt; page. right now only 2 are there. so sad!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;oh, i also put the site up on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/js044/nenrikido&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. i&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep the code up to date. anyways feel free to poke around. i&amp;rsquo;m a big copyright hater so go nuts with copy/pasting, just please no hotlinking, and if you use anything i didn&amp;rsquo;t write/make, please be mindful of attribution. the code is still pretty messy, but ah well. transparency and whatnot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i think those are all the site updates i have for now. tbh i&amp;rsquo;m just procrastinating stuff and wanted an excuse to post the bavarian village fujoshi tweet but anyways have a good day. remember to drink water and whatnot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT: added some more &lt;a href=&#34;./about.html#personality-quizzes&#34;&gt;personality quiz results&lt;/a&gt; too&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reusable HTML Snippets: Web Components</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/web-components/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 02:32:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/web-components/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;first off, here&amp;rsquo;s the demo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;codepen&#34; data-height=&#34;413&#34; data-default-tab=&#34;html,result&#34; data-slug-hash=&#34;OJoopqa&#34; data-user=&#34;kujara1&#34; style=&#34;height: 300px; box-sizing: border-box; display: flex; align-items: center; justify-content: center; border: 2px solid; margin: 1em 0; padding: 1em;&#34;&gt; &lt;span&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href=&#34;https://codepen.io/kujara1/pen/OJoopqa&#34;&gt; web components card demo&lt;/a&gt; by jay (&lt;a href=&#34;https://codepen.io/kujara1&#34;&gt;@kujara1&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&#34;https://codepen.io&#34;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;script async src=&#34;https://cpwebassets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-coding-backstory-sad-violin&#34;&gt;my coding backstory (sad violin)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the first time i made a Real Website (cicada), i had never heard of &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.getdbt.com/terms/dry&#34;&gt;DRY code&lt;/a&gt;. DRY stands for &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t repeat yourself,&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s often cited as one of the most important guiding principles for both backend and frontend coding. it &lt;a href=&#34;https://dev.to/wuz/stop-trying-to-be-so-dry-instead-write-everything-twice-wet-5g33&#34;&gt;isn&amp;rsquo;t a hard rule&lt;/a&gt;, but the consensus tends to be that if you repeat the same code more than three times, you may want to consider making it repeatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but i didn&amp;rsquo;t know this back then. my experience was limited to single pages and tumblr themes, so i&amp;rsquo;d never thought about page management before. at first, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t so bad. copying and pasting the stylesheets, scripts, header, footer—it&amp;rsquo;s manageable for your core pages. but we were running a litmag, and this meant publishing issues that were usually at least 30 pages, and sometimes hit over 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i dreaded the task every semester. it was a time consuming and tedious nightmare that no one wanted to help me with (for obvious reasons.) invariably, i&amp;rsquo;d mess up the copy and pasting at some point, and then multiple pages would have mistakes. i had to explain to our managing editor that it&amp;rsquo;d take days to change any navigation links because i&amp;rsquo;d have to manually update every single page. he just stared at me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i knew this was Wrong, but i kept telling myself that this wasn&amp;rsquo;t my real job, so i had no reason to learn a better way—i was a graphic design major, not a computer scientist! this was just my flimsy bandaid solution until a proper web developer finally applied and saved the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that never happened. CCM has existed since 2018, and we have never had one single person apply to be web developer. it has always just been me, tearfully wondering if that numb feeling in my wrist was of concern as i tried to copy and paste dozens of pages worth of identical content. things came to a head when i discovered that i&amp;rsquo;d been paying money for a dynamic site host when i could have been hosting it for free. embarrassing! harrowing! exhausting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i felt defeated. there was so much i didn&amp;rsquo;t know and i was at a loss of where to even begin. i knew so little that i didn&amp;rsquo;t even know the right search terms to input. there is so much information floating out there that it&amp;rsquo;s overwhelming. i considered giving up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;instead, i took the site down for 6 months and learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;static-site-generators&#34;&gt;static site generators&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;what i ultimately did was use a static site generator, which i highly recommend for anyone with a project that has as many pages as we did. i used hugo, and although i haven&amp;rsquo;t tried out other static site generators, i am deeply in love with it to the point it now feels weird making stuff without it. the learning curve is intimidating, and it takes a lot of time to get comfortable with it, but you&amp;rsquo;ll get there. i struggled a lot because i had to create a theme from scratch and the theme had a lot of interactive components that i didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough skill to execute effectively, but the hugo community was super helpful and active. and if you&amp;rsquo;re using pre-made themes, it&amp;rsquo;s not hard to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;hugo elegantly resolves the issue of repeatable code snippets through things like &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/templates/partials/&#34;&gt;partials&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. static site generators in general were formulated with goals like this in mind. jekyll lets you use &lt;a href=&#34;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/includes/&#34;&gt;includes&lt;/a&gt; and gatsby has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gatsbyjs.com/docs/how-to/routing/layout-components/&#34;&gt;layout components&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;static site generators aim to make things very, very simple for you. they tend to prioritize markdown over HTML and encourage modularity in all design components. this is excellent for information, text-dense websites in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but maybe it&amp;rsquo;s not so great for people who have small websites, for people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to be bound by templates (even of their own creation), or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just more support than you need. and it certainly presents an additional challenge when deploying somewhere like neocities. so are there other solutions?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;web-components&#34;&gt;web components&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i recognized a familiar feeling as i was working on this site. i was copying and pasting the card header, which is a bit dense due to how it&amp;rsquo;s constructed (bootstrap columns + fontawesome icons). by the 20th card header across pages, i was officially twitchy. then, as i was copying and pasting my start menu, my brain started melting. i cannot go through this again, i decided. i&amp;rsquo;d told myself it&amp;rsquo;d be fine since it&amp;rsquo;s only a few pages, but it&amp;rsquo;s too late. i know the truth now. there&amp;rsquo;s no good reason to repeat components that often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it made me realize i still fundamentally hadn&amp;rsquo;t found a solution for repeatable HTML components. sure, static site generators can solve that issue for me, but how was i going to do with a service like neocities that was intentionally whittled down to the bare essentials?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a lot of people on neocities seem to like iframes, but i don&amp;rsquo;t think they&amp;rsquo;re well-suited to this particular use-case. they&amp;rsquo;re not simple code snippet injections, they&amp;rsquo;re entire html files being injected into another html file. you have to style each individual iframe because it won&amp;rsquo;t inherit the parent page&amp;rsquo;s styling—which ends up undermining the goal of keeping your code DRY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cue&amp;hellip;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/reusable-html-components-how-to-reuse-a-header-and-footer-on-a-website/&#34;&gt;web components&lt;/a&gt;!! mdn docs cover web components &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/Web_Components&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as well. long story short, web components are a suite of tools you can utilize with vanilla javascript to create all sorts of repeatable code. i&amp;rsquo;ve been told they funtion a lot like react.js components. here&amp;rsquo;s a crash course video on web components and the accompanying &lt;a href=&#34;https://codepen.io/bradtraversy/pen/wvaXKoK&#34;&gt;codepen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;yt&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PCWaFLy3VUo&#34; title=&#34;Web Components Crash Course&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;as of writing this, i&amp;rsquo;ve only needed to use custom elements, which are fairly simple to use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;first, you create your reusable HTML snippet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;then, you create a javascript file, decide on the name of your component, and build it. the syntax generally looks like this:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt; &lt;code&gt;
class TITLE extends HTMLElement {
    constructor() {
    super();
    this.innerHTML = `insert your HTML here`;
     }
       }
  window.customElements.define(&#39;TITLE-ID&#39;, TITLE)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;  
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;from there, you can link the component and invoke the code in your HTML like &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;TITLE-ID&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/TITLE-ID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;note: your title-id must be two words combined with a hyphen. your title can be whatever you like though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;note: remember to include the &lt;code&gt;`&lt;/code&gt; tags when you insert your HTML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i currently use six components and they alone have saved me well over 1k lines of code. hopefully you find some utility in this post and can get started with repeatable snippets too. love &amp;amp; peace on planet earth!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>misogyny online</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/misogyny-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 03:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/misogyny-online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;i wasn&amp;rsquo;t really planning on posting about discourse, esp. since a lot of people seem to use this part of the web to escape it, but oh well. i was pretty much born on tumblr; it&amp;rsquo;s where i learned to code, and alas, it is also where i learned to get irritated during 3AM scrolling sessions. and lord forgive me for i have scrolled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but anyways, something that just drives me insane is the wave of cutesy, unbearable MRA-ish rhetoric that has been circulating that site for the last few years. a lesbian will get online and make an obviously satirical post about how men should be feminine, and before you know it, the comments are filled with people posting pics of the most mid white men you&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen and super subversive takes like &amp;ldquo;let men be masculine.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s so unserious i can&amp;rsquo;t take it. it&amp;rsquo;s also crazy to me that half the userbase will readily admit this is their way of owning the misandrists or whatever. like lmao, if you&amp;rsquo;re such a reactionary AHEM i mean contrarian that you can get goaded into full-blown anti-feminism because of 200 note tumblr posts then you need to get a grip. like i don&amp;rsquo;t care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i don&amp;rsquo;t understand how you can get online and make a post like &amp;ldquo;ummm did you know women,,,, can lie,,,&amp;rdquo; and think you&amp;rsquo;ve said something illuminating. like wow, you are so brave and strong for regurgitating cultural narratives that have dominated society for hundreds of years. but right, &amp;ldquo;we don&amp;rsquo;t talk enough&amp;rdquo; about how women can be bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and it&amp;rsquo;s so funny bc most of these people would likely describe themselves as feminists. i think it speaks to a broader issue where people treat ideologies like stickers to decorate a name tag rather than complex schools of thought. there could be thousands of books on a topic dating back since the written word began and you&amp;rsquo;d still have a bunch of people distilling it into 10 words or less and thinking they&amp;rsquo;re qualified to be experts on the topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i try really hard to be patient about it. &amp;ldquo;they&amp;rsquo;re just working things out,&amp;rdquo; i tell myself. &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s normal to have some growing pains.&amp;rdquo; but they are so smug, so self-assured as they go, &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s so simple!&amp;rdquo; about topics that are anything but. and it&amp;rsquo;s infuriating because you want to scream, of COURSE it&amp;rsquo;s simple when you flatten a complex topic into a singular witty tweet. it&amp;rsquo;s easy to do that. i could do that! but it would be vapid and ultimately a disservice to my politics! your garbled TLDR will never stand up to scrutiny because you haven&amp;rsquo;t given it an iota of thought!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HOW on earth you can feel comfortable assuming a tone of confident authority when you do not understand the most fundamental basics of what you&amp;rsquo;re speaking as an authority about is beyond me. but it happens ALLLLLL the time. it&amp;rsquo;s why you have people with hammer &amp;amp; sickle pins on their kankens who&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of &amp;amp; do not care to know about the labor theory of value, why people who are most condescendingly vocal about antiracism are often the first to microaggress you at a work meeting, and also why people feel comfortable calling themselves feminists when their idea of activism is saying &amp;ldquo;let women wear makeup!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s this brand of &amp;ldquo;activism&amp;rdquo; that says you don&amp;rsquo;t have to really do anything. you don&amp;rsquo;t have to examine your biases or question why society is structured the way it is. you don&amp;rsquo;t have to study or read or think. all you have to do is convince yourself you&amp;rsquo;re ontologically good and incapable of harm and slap on a handful of labels and boom! you&amp;rsquo;re progressive. but to me, that&amp;rsquo;s just fashion. that&amp;rsquo;s not real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i could make a much longer and more emotional post about how this really, really hit me when tara reade credibly accused biden of rape and everyone tore her to shreds. i realized that the &amp;ldquo;solidarity&amp;rdquo; with women people showed during #metoo was all posturing. people are feminists when it&amp;rsquo;s politically convenient. it was the first of many times that i would realize how tissue paper thin people&amp;rsquo;s allyship generally is, not just when it comes to feminism, but tara reade&amp;rsquo;s story really got to me. i felt really hopeless about it for a long time. still do, a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a decent number of leftists came out in support of tara reade, but a sizable chunk later revealed they were really only trying to ~stick it to the neolibs~ and never truly cared. it was just a convenient political bludgeon to gleefully point out the hypocrisy of &amp;ldquo;believe women&amp;rdquo; turning into &amp;ldquo;what was she wearing&amp;rdquo; within minutes. but in reality, those same leftists are out here making jokes about how &amp;ldquo;when the revolution comes we get to fuck the boss&amp;rsquo; wife!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but if i say &amp;ldquo;this relies on misogynistic logic that frames women as spoils of war, passive agents who only exist to be sexually humiliated as proxies to hurt the men in their lives, this is why i don&amp;rsquo;t trust your allyship,&amp;rdquo; i&amp;rsquo;m the bad guy. i&amp;rsquo;m divisive, a leftist infighter, a naughty feminist ruining the joke. like, fine then. that is fine with me. sure. i will get a shirt that says i &amp;lt;3 leftist infighting because i&amp;rsquo;m very willing to die on the hill that women&amp;rsquo;s rights aren&amp;rsquo;t superfluous add-ons like extra onions on your discourse sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this is already getting way longer than i meant for it to, but another thing!! i remember when andrew tate was arrested, there was this semi-popular post that was like, &amp;ldquo;i don&amp;rsquo;t care about his rhetorical misogyny, i care he was trafficking women!!&amp;rdquo; and i think that perfectly illuminates what i&amp;rsquo;m so fed up with. this idea that misogyny is purely discursive and has no bearing on material reality is so pervasive online so OF COURSE the discourse is incoherent and divorced from reality and i am so so so soooo so so so sick of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but i&amp;rsquo;m glad i now understand what a lot of people are really doing when they finger wag at me about politics. they are wearing ideology as fashion, as aesthetic, as a brand, and they&amp;rsquo;ll abandon it in a heartbeat when it isn&amp;rsquo;t trendy anymore. and when they do, i&amp;rsquo;ll still be here, as always, listening to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dg9nULGeMcc&#34;&gt;mitski scream compliation&lt;/a&gt;. what else is a girl to do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;other updates:&lt;/strong&gt; (1) helping my friend with their portfolio site &amp;amp; thesis page, it looks pretty banger imo. i discovered you can password protect https pages &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.maxlaumeister.com/pagecrypt/&#34;&gt;pretty easily&lt;/a&gt; too! (2) still working on moving, it&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of a mess&amp;hellip; (3) i checked out some neopets userlookup stuff bc i thought it&amp;rsquo;d be fun to make a few themes and put them on my code page, but my god the styling options are so limited. everything is bound by tables to begin with, which&amp;hellip;bruh. i mean i get why &amp;amp; i still wanna try it out but i&amp;rsquo;m just sooo spoiled by css variables and media queries now. you can&amp;rsquo;t even use css grids!! oh, the agony.. (4) rewatched madoka magica. cried again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Website (Part 1): The Planning Stage</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/making-a-website-pt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 03:22:37 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/making-a-website-pt-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The blog got a bit of a makeover! Anyways, this is the first post in a series I&amp;rsquo;ve planned about building websites. It&amp;rsquo;s aimed towards the absolute beginner, but hopefully, it&amp;rsquo;ll still be interesting or useful for people with more experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find coding to be similar to many other creative processes. Like cooking, drawing, or writing, it helps save a lot of time and effort to plan out your project beforehand. This is true even if you don&amp;rsquo;t plan for your site to be elaborately designed. It is useful to establish (1) what kind of information you&amp;rsquo;ll have on your site and (2) how you want this information displayed and organized. This will help you select (3) the tools you&amp;rsquo;ll need for your project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;1-information&#34;&gt;(1) Information&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some questions you might ask yourself: what is your site about? What sorts of pages do you want on your website? How many of them will there be? Are you interested in making a &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hubspot.com/website/static-vs-dynamic-website&#34;&gt;static website or a dynamic website?&lt;/a&gt; is your site professional or personal? Are there any special features you want your website to have (such as password-protected sections, contact forms, shops, etc.)? Do you want a community-oriented site or one that&amp;rsquo;s more standalone? Is the site image-heavy and therefore in need of space considerations? All of this will be relevant when it&amp;rsquo;s time to choose web hosting, come up with designs, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s a huge difference in use-case between a 5-page static site on Neocities and a dynamic blog with hundreds of pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;2-design&#34;&gt;(2) Design&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have a general idea of what you want your site to be like, it&amp;rsquo;s less daunting to start researching other sites/designs and sketching out preliminary ideas. &lt;a href=&#34;https://pin.it/6lo2wph&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; the pinterest board I put together when I was working on this site. You can definitely tell where I pulled inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here&amp;rsquo;s an excerpt from some of the design brainstorming I did for this website. (there are currently 6 pages worth of drafting and notes in total&amp;hellip;lol)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;./images/blog/planning.jpg&#34; data-lightbox=&#34;planning &#34;&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;./images/blog/planning.jpg&#34; class=&#34;img-fluid&#34; loading=&#34;&#34;  width=&#34;&#34; height=&#34;&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that I am still considering information and where I want it to go—these steps build off each other and aren&amp;rsquo;t always going to happen in perfect sequential order. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible things will end up being very different once you actually start coding (for example, I ended up ditching the different colored cards in favor of themes.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When designing (and coding), it can help to think of sites in components: there&amp;rsquo;s the header, the body, and the footer. You may or may not want sidebars. Also consider how you want people to interact with your site components. What do you want to happen when someone clicks on an image? Do you want &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.w3schools.com/css/css_tooltip.asp&#34;&gt;tooltips?&lt;/a&gt; what should happen to links when you hover? You don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to have all these answers right away, as a lot of finer details get ironed out as you work on your site, but thinking about these things ahead of time can help you prepare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes on design:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are a variety of best practices for design that are outside the scope of this post. You can start &lt;a href=&#34;https://webflow.com/blog/web-design-for-beginners&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for some pointers on things like thinking in grids and considering color theory. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.feelingpeaky.com/9-principles-of-good-web-design/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; article also outlines 9 specific design principles that can help guide you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s possible (likely, even) that there will be elements in your planned design that you do not know how to implement yet. That is okay! You are learning. Don&amp;rsquo;t get discouraged. There are a multitude of tools out there to help you bring your idea to the life, and ultimately, even if you have to temper your design to match your current skill level, it&amp;rsquo;s still a good learning experience to logic through some of these design issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;3-tools&#34;&gt;(3) Tools&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a ton of tools to get you started building websites. This is amazing for many reasons, but it can get overwhelming really quickly. Getting your ideas off paper and onto the screen isn&amp;rsquo;t always as easy as you&amp;rsquo;d like, but hopefully these notes can give you a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes on CSS libraries &amp;amp; frameworks:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if responsonsive displays are important to you (your website looking good on mobile &amp;amp; tablets in addition to desktop), I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend using a CSS library or framework. I have a few listed on my &lt;a href=&#34;links.html#web-dev-resources&#34;&gt;links&lt;/a&gt; page under the resources section. If you care about responsiveness but don&amp;rsquo;t want to commit to a css library or framework, you can also tools like the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cssgrid-generator.netlify.app/&#34;&gt;CSS grid generator&lt;/a&gt; listed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;css libraries &amp;amp; frameworks all have their pros/cons. Bootstrap is robust and easy to use, but it can also be very opinionated when it comes to design. If you&amp;rsquo;re also opinionated, you may find yourself butting heads with it and working to override styles. Tailwind, on the other hand, is more design-agnostic but requires a bit more set-up. You may prefer semantic or utility classes. You may want a lightweight library or a more comprehensive one. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to know what you personally prefer until you try a few out, and different situations will be better suited to different libraries &amp;amp; frameworks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes on static site generators:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I do not have a section on my resources page (yet!) &amp;amp; it&amp;rsquo;s a bit beyond the scope of this post, but if you&amp;rsquo;re planning on a site with many, many pages, it might be useful for you to use a static site generator like Hugo, Jekyll, or Gatsby. You can find a comprehensive list &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamstack.org/generators/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or learn more about the function of ssgs &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/learning/performance/static-site-generator/&#34;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please note there isn&amp;rsquo;t much documentation on using static site generators in conjunction with Neocities. If you are interested in using static site generators with Neocities, &lt;a href=&#34;https://neonaut.neocities.org/neocities/&#34;&gt;here&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; an example of someone using Hugo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes on web hosting &amp;amp; deployment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a smorgasbord of options when it comes to hosting &amp;amp; deploying sites online. I&amp;rsquo;m using Neocities because I think the community element is interesting, but it&amp;rsquo;s far from the only option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re creating a static site, you might consider options like Github Pages, Netlify, or Neocities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re working on a complex dynamic site, you might be more interested in something like Heroku, Firebase, or Azure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Note: there is a difference between dynamic server-side rendered websites (which use tools like php &amp;amp; node.js) and dynamic client-side websites (which use tools like React &amp;amp; Vue). Some sites known for static site hosting may be able to host dynamic client-side websites—for example, Github Pages can host the latter, but not the former.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About Neocities specifically: Neocities is intentionally very simple. This can either be a strength or weakness depending on your use-case. You won&amp;rsquo;t be able to use a lot of tools that exist to make things easier and faster, but this also means the barrier of entry is much lower. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t be simpler to upload to Neocities, but this also means that complicated sites can get unwieldy very fast if you don&amp;rsquo;t have much experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ll wrap the post up here. Partly because it&amp;rsquo;s 3 AM and partly because i think this is a good starting point for anyone interested in building a site. I have a few ideas of what part 2 should cover, but if you have any suggestions, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for personal life stuff: rewatched Serial Experiments Lain recently &amp;amp; started rewatching Utena, which is causing two very different aesthetic sensibilities to bleed together in my brain. Feeling vaguely inspired to smash rose &amp;amp; tech motifs together in an upcoming theme, but only time will tell if this is genius or terrible. (still need to make that code page, now that i think about it&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;edit: ok, awake now and edited this post a bit, added a few things, fixed some wording, and messed with mobile blog displays&amp;hellip;yeah. Time to work on some cicada stuff now 🫡&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#39;why&#39;d you make this site?&#39;, &#39;how did you start coding?&#39;, and other questions</title>
      <link>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/whyd-you-make-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 22:59:17 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nenrikido.neocities.org/blog/post/whyd-you-make-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;my 26th birthday was earlier this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;once you reach a certain age, the birthday wishes can take on an anxious &amp;ldquo;what-are-you-doing-with-your-life&amp;rdquo; cadence. i&amp;rsquo;m single, i&amp;rsquo;m not gainfully employed, and i dropped the MLIS pipe dream when i was forced to accept that i don&amp;rsquo;t have $15k laying around. so i can understand a thinly veiled concern text from people who believe success is marked by homeownership and cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but in the midst of the furrowed brows and loaded questions about my life, i just kept thinking, &amp;ldquo;damn, i never made that neocities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;making a neocities has been a &amp;ldquo;thing i&amp;rsquo;ll do when my skills are good enough&amp;rdquo; for years now. truthfully, i&amp;rsquo;m still not comfortable with my skill level, and i don&amp;rsquo;t know if i ever will be. but on my 26th birthday, i was sitting there, sadly twirling my complimentary birthday joint, reflecting on my neocities-lessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i, like many other neocities users, got started with front-end coding by fiddling with tumblr themes. (well, technically, i first messed with HTML as an elementary schooler trying to get mcr teenagers to autoplay on my sasunaru themed neopets page, but i really started learning with tumblr.) i was (am) a bit (a lot) of a control freak, and i liked the control i was given over my own space, especially on an internet that was growing increasingly homogenous and bland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way since i was a teenager meticulously decorating my blog with danganronpa renders and misusing css combinators, but i&amp;rsquo;ve adamantly maintained that it&amp;rsquo;s valuable to stake your space online and loudly voice your displeasure with corporate internet interests. i&amp;rsquo;ve invested literally hundreds of hours into understanding the ins and outs of static site generators and css frameworks. i&amp;rsquo;ve spent months banging my head against walls, posting on stackoverflow, and scouring docs, all in service of making things look and behave the way i want them to. (and specifically for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cicadacreativemag.com/&#34;&gt;cicada website&lt;/a&gt;, which i have now coded from the ground-up four different times. it is even more painful than you think.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the effort has paid off in some pretty big ways. this website has taken me a fraction of the time it would&amp;rsquo;ve a few years ago. i look at old code and cringe, but i know how i&amp;rsquo;d rewrite it now. i inch towards becoming more secure in my knowledge base every time i open a code editor. but my perfectionism can be debilitating and chasing some mythical &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; standard has ultimately been destructive for my creativity (and overall happiness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;anyways, i realized a few things as the smoke (literally) cleared. first, i needed to make a neocities. not eventually. right now! it might be a mess, but it&amp;rsquo;d be my mess, and i need to learn to let things be in-progress. second, i wanted to help other people make their own sites, and hopefully mitigate a bit of the head-banging inherent in coding. that is more important to me than impressing people who think money measures your worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so for me, this site also functions as a bit of resistance. resistance against the idea that efficiency is inherently more important than creativity, resistance against the idea that hobbies are a waste of time unless you can turn a profit, and resistance against the notion that everything must be polished and perfect and professional all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i want to use this blog specifically to post helpful guides (once i get the rest of the site coded, that is&amp;hellip;) and help make HTML/CSS more accessible to people with zero formal exposure. i also want this site as a whole to be proof that even a certified tumblrina faildaughter can contribute to communities, even in small ways. if even one person lifts a chunk of code off this site, i&amp;rsquo;ll take it as a win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;so, in lieu of doing a normal adult activity to mark the milestone of being closer to 30 than 20, i have spent the last week huddled over my laptop trying to make this site work. and honestly, i feel pretty good about it. i even feel good about how long this blog post is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;all this to say: nice to meet you! do not give in! consider making a website! talk to you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
